<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Common Variant on Van der Laan &amp; Science</title>
    <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/tags/common-variant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Common Variant on Van der Laan &amp; Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 1979-2018 Sander W. van der Laan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swvanderlaan.github.io/tags/common-variant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mendelian randomisation</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/project/mendelian-randomisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/project/mendelian-randomisation/</guid>
      <description>Mendel&amp;rsquo;s Second Law, the law of independent assortment, underlies the principle of Mendelian randomisation (MR) which make use of the inherent properties of the human genome to enable causal inference for a biomarker. The invariant nature of the genome, and the random distribution of alleles from parents to offspring at the time of conception (Mendel&amp;rsquo;s Second Law), imply that the genetic information is not influenced by disease status or the presence of risk factors (reverse causality), therefore it should be free from confounding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiovascular genetics</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/project/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/project/genetics/</guid>
      <description>At the start of the Human Genome Project, its promise was to not deliver new druggable targets, rather to increase our knowledge of the human genome, its organisation and its contents. Now, decades later, and fuelled by advances in genotyping technology, genome-wide association studies (GWAS) have robustly associated thousands of variants to hundreds of traits and diseases. While these have vastly increased, and confirmed, our understanding of the genetic underpinnings of common diseases, such as coronary artery disease (CAD) and ischemic stroke, they fall short of precisely explaining the underlying biological mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>