<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Van der Laan &amp; Science</title>
    <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Van der Laan &amp; Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 1979-2019 Sander W. van der Laan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A functional locus at 8q21.13 associates to FABP4 levels and is modulated by BMI and kidney function</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/ashg2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/ashg2017/</guid>
      <description>The abstract can be found at the ASHG 2017 site and will be integrated here after the conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic susceptibility loci for coronary artery disease and large artery stroke are associated with human atherosclerotic plaque characteristics</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/eshg2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/eshg2016/</guid>
      <description>S.W. van der Laan1, M.A. Siemelink1, S. Haitjema1, H. Foroughi Asl2, M. Mokry1, J. van Setten1, R. Malik3, M. Dichgans3, B.B. Worrall4, N.J. Samani5,6, H. Schunkert7, J. Erdmann7, U. Hedin2, G. Paulsson-Berne2, J.L.M. Björkegren2, G. de Borst1, F.W. Asselbergs1,8,9, H.M. de Ruijter1, P.I.W. de Bakker1, G. Pasterkamp1 1) Laboratory of Experimental Cardiology, Division Heart &amp;amp; Lungs, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 2) Cardiovascular Genomics Group, Division of Vascular Biology, Department of Medical Biochemistry and Biophysics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden; 3) Molecular Medicine and Surgery, Karolinska Instutet, Stockholm, Sweden; 4) Institute for Stroke and Dementia Research, Medical Center Ludwig-Maximilians-University Münich, Münich, Germany; 5) Departments of Neurology and Public Health Sciences, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia, United States of America; 6) Department of Cardiovascular Sciences, University of Leicester, BHF Cardiovascular Research Centre, Glenfield Hospital, Leicester, United Kingdom; 7) NIHR Leicester Cardiovascular Biomedical Research Unit, Glenfield Hospital, Leicester, United Kingdom; 8) Deutsches Herzzentrum München, Klinik an der TU München, Munich Heart Alliance (DZHK), Münich, Germany; 9) Unit of Cardiovascular Medicine, Department of Medicine, CMM, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden; 10) Department of Surgery, Division of Surgical Specialties, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 11) Department of Cardiology, Division Heart &amp;amp; Lungs, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 12) Durrer Center for Cardiogenetic Research, ICIN-Netherlands Heart Institute, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 13) Institute of Cardiovascular Science, Faculty of Population Health Sciences, University College London, London, United Kingdom; 14) Department of Medical Genetics, Center for Molecular Medicine, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 15) Department of Epidemiology, Julius Center for Health Sciences and Primary Care, University Medical Center Utrecht, the Netherlands; 16) Laboratory of Clinical Chemistry and Hematology, Division Laboratories and Pharmacy, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic analyses of atherosclerosis and plaque characteristics</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/dgjm2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/dgjm2016/</guid>
      <description>I was invited to talk about our work regarding the impact of cardiovascular risk loci on histological plaque characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atheroma tissue and pathway validation (Athero-Express)</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/cvc2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/cvc2016/</guid>
      <description>I was invited to talk about our work regarding the genetic architecture of atherosclerotic plaque characteristics and the underling gene networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A common variant associated with coronary artery disease increases atheroma size within atherosclerotic plaques of patients with carotid stenosis</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/eshg2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/eshg2015/</guid>
      <description>S.W. van der Laan1, J. van Setten1, H.M. den Ruijter1, F.W. Asselbergs1, P.I.W. de Bakker2, G. Pasterkamp1 1) UMC Utrecht, Utrecht, Netherlands, 2) Program in Medical and Population Genetics, Broad Institute, Cambridge (MA), United States of America.
Background To date, genome-wide association studies have identified 2 susceptibility loci for large artery ischemic stroke and 45 loci for coronary artery disease (CAD). We investigated whether these SNPs affected atherosclerotic plaque characteristics in the Athero-Express Biobank Study (AE) of patients with clinically significant carotid stenosis, from whom plaque specimens have been histologically analyzed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cystatin C and cardiovascular disease: a Mendelian randomization study</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/isa-cvc2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/isa-cvc2015/</guid>
      <description>S.W. van der Laan1, T. Fall2, J. van Setten1,3, P.I.W. de Bakker3,4, G. Pasterkamp1, J. Ärnlöv2, M.V. Holmes5, F.W. Asselbergs3,6,7,8 on behalf of the Cystatin C MR Consortium. 1) Experimental Cardiology, UMC Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 2) Department of Medical Sciences, Uppsala Uni- versity, Uppsala, Sweden; 3) Department of Medical Genetics, UMC Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 4) Julius Center for Health Sciences and Primary Care, UMC Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 5) Penn Medicine, University of Pennsylvania Health System, United States of America; 6) Institute of Cardiovascular Science, Faculty of Population Health Sciences, University College London, London, United Kingdom; 7) Durrer Center for Cardiogene- tic Research, ICIN-Netherlands Heart Institute, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 8) Department of Cardiology, UMC Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cystatin C and cardiovascular disease: a Mendelian randomization study</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/ashg2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/ashg2014/</guid>
      <description>S.W. van der Laan1, T. Fall2, J. van Setten1,3, P.I.W. de Bakker3,4, G. Pasterkamp1, J. Ärnlöv2, M.V. Holmes5, F.W. Asselbergs3,6,7,8 on behalf of the Cystatin C MR Consortium. 1) Experimental Cardiology, UMC Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 2) Department of Medical Sciences, Uppsala Uni- versity, Uppsala, Sweden; 3) Department of Medical Genetics, UMC Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 4) Julius Center for Health Sciences and Primary Care, UMC Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 5) Penn Medicine, University of Pennsylvania Health System, United States of America; 6) Institute of Cardiovascular Science, Faculty of Population Health Sciences, University College London, London, United Kingdom; 7) Durrer Center for Cardiogene- tic Research, ICIN-Netherlands Heart Institute, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 8) Department of Cardiology, UMC Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Genetic Evidence that Common Variants near PIK3CG are Associated with Atherosclerotic Plaque Hemorrhage and Vessel Density</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/eshg2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/eshg2014/</guid>
      <description>S.W. van der Laan1, L. Folkersen2, J. van Setten1, A.H. Schoneveld1, S.M. van de Weg1, F.W. Asselbergs1, D.P.V. de Kleijn3,4, R. Malik5, M. Dichgans5, A. Gabrielsen2, P.I.W. de Bakker1,6, G. Pasterkamp1 1) UMC Utrecht, Utrecht, Netherlands, 2) Karolinska Institute, Stockholm, Sweden, 3) Interuniversity Cardiology Institute of the Netherlands, Utrecht, Netherlands, 4) National University of Singapore, Singapore, Singapore, 5) Institute for Stroke and Dementia Research, München, Germany, 6) Program in Medical and Population Genetics, Broad Institute, Cambridge (MA), United States of America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Genome–Wide Association Study of Plaque Phenotypes in the Athero–Express Biobank Study</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/eas2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/talk/eas2012/</guid>
      <description>Sander W. van der Laan1,2, Jessica van Setten3, Arjan H. Schoneveld2, Sander M. van de Weg2, Claudia Tersteeg2, Chaylendra Strijder2, Mirjam B. Smeets2, Folkert W. Asselbergs3,4, Jean-Paul de Vries5, Frans L. Moll5, Dominique P.V. de Kleijn1,2, Paul I.W. de Bakker3,6,7, Gerard Pasterkamp1,2 1) Interuniversity Cardiology Institute of the Netherlands, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 2) Experimental Cardiology Laboratory, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 3) Department of Medical Genetics, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 4) Department of Cardiology, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 5) Department of Vascular Surgery, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands; 6) Program in Medical and Population Genetics, Broad Institute, Cambridge, Massachusetts; 7) Department of Medicine, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>