<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Van der Laan &amp; Science</title>
    <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Van der Laan &amp; Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 1979-2018 Sander W. van der Laan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swvanderlaan.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I got R with tcl-tk on my Mac</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/post/getting-r-with-tcl-tk-on-my-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/post/getting-r-with-tcl-tk-on-my-mac/</guid>
      <description>Background Sometimes data is very skewed and contains a lot of &amp;lsquo;zeros&amp;rsquo; (or very small numbers approaching &amp;lsquo;zero&amp;rsquo;). Before analyses such data need normalisation to meet the assumptions of a statistical test (you can find more on transformation and normalisation here). Usually people log-transform (e.g. natural log, or log2), the disadvantage is that you loose the &amp;lsquo;zeros&amp;rsquo;.
In my case that is an issue, because the measurements made were properly done (no technical issues), so &amp;lsquo;zero&amp;rsquo; really represents &amp;lsquo;zero&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I setup my Mac to do Science in 2018</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/post/setting-up-my-mac-for-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/post/setting-up-my-mac-for-science/</guid>
      <description>Background I prefer to use brew to install the &amp;lsquo;missing&amp;rsquo; libraries on macOS that come in handy, like weget, or imagemagick, or rename. In addition, I work on the analyses of histological slides, and for that I use slideToolkit which also requires brew on macOS.
So, I thought, &amp;ldquo;might as well go full monty&amp;rdquo; and install R and RStudio using brew. This provides me with a powerful method to control many packages/libraries that are needed for macOS and at the same time creates a very clean R environment on my Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I maintain my Hugo-based website on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/post/my-hugo-2-github-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/post/my-hugo-2-github-setup/</guid>
      <description>Background I wanted to create this website and make it fast and easy for me to update it. I learned of jekyll via GitHub, but also learned that hugo works much faster to enhance my personal website. With hugo I would still be able to use Github Pages to host the generated html files (in the Public folder). Googling I discovered several methods (the hugo-method wasn&amp;rsquo;t working for me either) which were not directly intuitive to me; in the end I found this post by Cheng-Jun Wang to be most helpful and best match my needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-inventing my academic self</title>
      <link>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/post/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swvanderlaan.github.io/post/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Today marks the day of re-inventing my academic self. As the genetics community ushers in what some refer to as the post-GWAS era, I feel things are falling to place for me. In the last couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a lot and formulating my plans for the next 3-5 years. My key-interests will involve:
 Functional cardiovascular genomics, including quantitative trait loci analyses using expression, protein and methylation datasets; Cardiovascular genetics, including rare and common variant analyses, loss-of-function analyses; Causal inference using Mendelian randomisation; High-throughput imaging and analysis through machine-learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>